3E帝国倾情奉献
中英字幕合并:算妮狠
抱歉
Excuse us.
借过
Get out of the way
阿信
Ashin
哥，你有没有怎样？
Brother, are you alright?
怎么这么严重啦
How can itbe so serious?
小心点
Be careful
阿信啊
Ashin,
抱歉，借过啊
Excuse us.
呵！这个猴囝子
What? This kid
真厉害喔！
He is good!
好像猴子喔！
Like a monkey!
什么好像猴子
Nonsense,
那可是我孙子勒！
He's my grandson.
怎么蹲的啊
Don't you know how to squat?
屁股坐下去
Lower your butt.
再下去
Lower.
再下去一点
Lower, much lower.
手抬高
Arms higher.
喂
Hey!
你是谁
Who are you?
你又不是体操队的
You're not in the gymnastic team.
进来干嘛
Why are you here?
出去
Get out!
走开啦
Don't get in the way.
现在开始倒立
Ready for handstand.
听口令
Attention!
一拍手
One, clap hands.
二把脚踏出来
Two, step out your feet.
三手放下去
Three, put down your hands.
后脚抬高高
Lift your legs high.
就像小狗撒尿
Just like a puppy peeping.
撑住
Hang in there.
你已经胖到脚都抬不起来罗
You're too fat to lift your leg.
抬高
Lift your legs.
脚抬起来
诶你香蕉腰喔
Your waist is as weak as a banana.
妈不是跟你说过
What have I told you?
上课要专心要认真听
You need to pay attention in school.
你怎么偷吃便当啊
How could you eat the lunchbox during class?
妈,  因为你卤的鸡腿实在太香了
Mom, the braised chicken thigh you made smelled so good.
还有理由喔
What an excuse.
要是我鸡腿用炸的
If I made fried chicken, then you'd
你不就上课走到半路就偷吃完了
finish iton the way to school.
妈
Mom,
我想要练体操好吗
can I practice gymnastics?
要交钱吗
Do we need to pay for that?
教练说不用
The coach said no.
不用钱就去啊
Then go for la.
手伸直
Straighten your arm,
不要撑
don't push.
很痛
It hurts.
好了啦
You may go.
下一位
Next.
看什么看
What are you looking at?
换你啦
It's your turn.
伸直伸直
Make itstraight.
伸直啦
Straight.
小树，不错喔
Shu, nice.
脚伸直
Straighten your legs.
挺胸
Thrust out your chest.
看前面
Look forward.
新来的喔
You're the new kid, right?
要加油喔
You need to work hard.
来，脚伸直
Come on. Straighten your legs.
挺胸，看前面
Thrust out your chest. Look forward.
你以为在拿方向盘开车啊
This is not a steering wheel.
回去重来
Go back and do itagain.
你是敢不敢跳啊
Are you going to jump or not?
今天要测验鞍马
Today is Pommel Horse skill test.
五圈加下马
5 circular motions then dismount.
来，谁先来
Come on. Who wants to go first?
谁先来啦
Any one?
伊冠钧
Champ Yi,
你先来
you go first.
预备姿势这么漂亮
Nice preparation posture but
一个都转不起来喔
can't even do one circular motion?
你就一个一个来嘛
Fine, you can do one at a time.
连下马都要分段喔
Even dismount is in sections.
回去回去回去
You can go back now.
维持好喔
Keep itthere.
高度维持好
Keep the height.
That's 30
停十秒
Hold itthere for 10 sec.
小树啊
Shu,
比赛就快到了
listen, the game is coming,
你就保持现在的状态
and you'll be fine if you keep
就没问题了
your current condition.
阿信啊，来
Ashin, come here.
你的弹跳力很好
You have great jumping power.
在空中的动作也很漂亮
Also have good moves in the air.
你为什么就是不会落地呢
But, why can't you land?
好，加油
Okay, try harder.
小树啊
Shu, Ashin's movements
阿信的动作越来越像你咧
are getting like yours.
大会报告大会报告
Attention please,
国小高年级组个人跳马决赛选手
Senior Student Group players in Individual Vault Event,
现在开始报到
please do the registry now.
大会报告
Attention please,
现在场地开放跳马项目
Three minutes practice time
决赛选手练习三分钟
for vault players.
为什么会这样
Why It Happened?
来来来，我来我来
Let me see.
怎么样
How do you feel?
脚扭到喔
Sprained your ankle?
脚先伸直
Straighten your legs first.
阿信啊
Ashin,
虽然你是个候补选手
as you're a substitute,
你就当这一次啊
just think this one
是一个练习
as a practice.
轻松一点
Take iteasy,
好不好
okay?
喔！还有
And, one more thing
只要你不摔个狗吃屎
As long as you don't fall on your face,
都行
la will be good enough.
加油
Go for la.
林育信
Lin Yu-Shin.
有
Here.
哥哥好棒喔！耶
Brother, you are great!
还在玩喔
Still playing?
吃饭了啦
Time for dinner.
妈
Mom,
你怎么没有来看我比赛
why didn't you come to my game?
我得到金牌勒
See, I won the gold medal!
靠那块金牌就会饱吗
Can you feed on the gold medal?
吃饭啦
Eat your dinner.
哥,金牌送我
Brother, give me your gold medal.
要金牌不会自己去拿喔
Go win your own.
妈,人家也要像哥哥一样
Mom, I want to be like brother.
练体操得金牌
Be a gymnast and win a gold medal.
什么金牌啦
Quit the medal thing.
你哥要吃屎你也要跟去吃屎吗
If he eats shit then you'll eat, too?
啊,不要啦
No.
我要跟哥哥一样啦
I wanna be like him
还要继续吵吗
You want to keep whining?
那我要拿藤条了喔！
Then I'll get my rattan.
不要不要
No, no, no.
会怕就好
Good.
唉哟！妈
Yuck! Mom,
那是什么
what's that?
唉哟什么
Yuck?
这我炖很久勒
I'd braised this for hours.
人家说“吃脑补脑”
"Eating brain enhances brain."
看你吃完会不会变得比较聪明
After eating this, maybe you can
比较会念书
be smarter and get higher grades.
呃     妈
Yuck! Mom,
这是什么脑啊
whose brain is la?
猪脑啊
Pig's brain.
我特地叫你阿娇姨帮我留的勒
I asked aunt Jiao to save this one for me.
一只猪只有一个
One pig has only one brain.
哈哈哈，吃完猪脑变猪头
Ha, you'll become a pig head.
你不要在那边笑
Don't you laugh at him.
你也要吃
You have to eat, too.
啊
No
啊   话不要那么多
No? No more moaning.
吃饭啦
Just eat.
活该
You deserve la.
林育信
Lin Yu-Shin.
有
Here.
阿信
Ashin,
你的直体笠松很直
your Kasamatsu Stretch is perfect.
动作也很漂亮
Your movements are great.
但是落地的时候 不管怎么样你都要站好嘛
But you need good landings.
小树
Shu
你动作都很好
your movements are great.
我可不可以拜托你
But,
脸不要这么臭
please don't wear this long face.
好不好
Okay?
观众跟裁判没人欠你钱耶
No one owes you money.
喔
Oh.
妈
Mom,
怎么这么久
what took you so long?
我肚子很饿勒
I'm starving.
哥，你脚怎么了
Brother, what's wrong with your foot?
那你下个月全国赛怎么办
What about your national game next month?
比什么赛
What game?
你也学一下你弟
Why can't you be like your little brother?
人家读书有在认真读
He studies hard and helps me
放学回家又会帮我顾水果摊
at the fruit stand after school.
那你呢
And you?
一天到晚就只会练体操练体操
All you know is gymnastics.
有本事你就不要受伤
If you're really good,
还要去给医生看
you'd better never get hurt.
要花多少钱你知道吗
The doctor visits are expensive.
我以后赚钱还你嘛
I'll earn money to pay you back later.
我就只想练体操啊
I just want to do gymnastics.
赚钱还我
Pay me back?
以后都不知道可不可以养活自己
I wonder if you can even feed yourself.
还想要赚钱还我
Let alone to repay me.
你如果继续练体操
If you keep doing gymnastics,
搞不好我要养你一辈子
I may need to support you forever.
长大了啊
A grown-up now.
都不知道自己的脚
Does he even know if his legs
是否有那个能力
are capable or not?
你真的不要再考虑一下
Are you really sure about this?
不要再让他继续练了好不好
Don't let him do this anymore.
黄教练
Please, Coach Huang.
他很不容易
It took him a lot
才能成为一位体操选手
to be a gymnast.
难道你要他就这样放弃
You really want him to stop?
体操我是不懂啦
I don't know about gymnastics.
我也知道我们阿信
But l know Ashin
一直都很认真
always practices hard.
不过黄教练
But, Coach Huang
你有看过体操选手
Have you seen any gymnast
是长短腿的吗
with uneven leg length?
阿信
Ashin.
你上来一下
Come up here.
喔
Okay.
教练
Coach.
妈
Mom?
你怎么在这里
Why are you here?
阿信啊
Ashin.
先把东西收一收
Pack your things,
跟你妈回去
and go home with your mom.
啊
What?
教练
Coach
叫你东西收一收你是没有听到是吗
Go pack your stuff, didn't you hear that?
每天就只想到练体操练体操
You care only gymnastics.
有想过要帮我做生意吗
How about helping the business?
妈
Mom
你几岁啊
How old are you now?
从现在开始
From now on,
不准你再练体操
no more gymnastics.
跟我回家学做生意卖水果
Stay home and learn the fruit business.
搞不好比练体操还有出息
It's a better prospect than gymnastics.
妈   拜托
Mom, please
教练
Coach
可是我快要比赛了勒
my game is coming.
我已经把你从比赛名单中剔除了
I've removed you from the list.
诶   你看
Hey, look.
这是我
This is me.
我昨天看到一个马子
I saw a chick yesterday.
拉一下
Pull la.
我看到她喔
I saw her.
很漂亮喔
She is pretty.
你拉一下这边
Pull here.
对
Right
很漂亮喔
See, she's pretty.
真正有影
What the hell.
今天要是再给我看到
If I see her today,
我一定把她变成“面筋”
I'll make her melted like cheese.
怎样
What?
你不会闪远一点喔
Don't get in the way.
不会啊
I don't want to move.
你想怎样
What do you want?
看你想怎么样啊
It depends on what do you want.
我哪知道你想要怎样
How would I know what you want?
看你想怎么样我就怎么样啦
I want what you want.
你要怎样就过来啦
Whatever. Come here if you dare.
不要在那边啦
Stop quacking there.
好啊！
Fine.
都不要动啦
Don't you move a step.
好吗
Okay.
啥小
What?
诶你要干嘛
What are you doing?
你要干嘛
你不要乱来，我的车
Don't do la. My car!
哥
Brother.
妈，我回来啰
Mom, I'm home.
不会自己拿给她哦
Why don't you give itto her?
你是在傻什么
Don't be silly.
去啦
Go,
真正有影
don't be so annoying.
妈
Mom.
钱是跟他有仇喔
Is money his enemy?
弄成这样
Folded like this
怎么少一百
How come itis 100 dollar short?
你自己问他啦
You ask him.
哥
Brother,
妈说怎么少一百
mom said there's 100 missing.
摩托车是吃水的喔
Do you think the motorcycle runs on water?
哥说
Brother said
我没有耳聋
I'm not deaf.
吃饭
Time to eat.
哥，妈说
Brother, mom said
知道啦
I know.
吃饭配电视就饱了啊
Having rice with TV is enough,
还需要吃菜吗
I guess you don't need any dishes.
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请输入您的CALL机号码
Please enter your pager number.
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请问您的CALL机密码是
May I have your pager password?
林先生您好
Hi, Mr. Lin.
今天中午12点10分
Today, at 12:10, Pickle said:
菜脯留言请您三点前到水闸门
Please be at the water gate before 3.
对方是眷村帮
The opponents are Mainlanders.
另外
And
他还要请您多带三把扁钻
please also bring 3 arrow chisels.
嗯
Okay.
整天到晚在外面乱晃
Fooling around all day.
是在做什么大生意
Like he is doing some huge business.
家里都待不住
Can't even stay home for a minute.
有办法就不要回来
Don't come home if you're that good!
唉哟
Well.
就你们四个
Only four of you.
找不到人喔
Can't find more help?
看是要跟谁打啦
It depends on whom we are fighting.
你们很嚣张嘛
You guys are very confident.
对～
Yap
现在后悔还来得及
it's not too late to regret.
来～
Come on.
抱歉
Sorry.
就是他们
It's them!
就是他们把我打成这样
They beat me into this.
说对不起
Say you're sorry.
你爸我就原谅你们
I'll forgive you son of a bitch.
上次没有把他手打断 算他运气好
He's lucky that we didn't break his arm last time.
这位看起来体格不错喔
This one looks well-built.
打下去不知道会不会叫妈妈
Wonder if he'll call momma later.
听不懂喔
You don't get la?
娃娃哭了
Baby calls his momma
不是要叫妈妈
when crying.
等一下谁叫妈还不知道勒
Don't know who'll call his mom yet.
警察来了
The police are here.
不要跑
Don't let him run away.
我来
I'll get him.
阿信
Ashin.
你是在干嘛啦
What are you doing?
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请问您的CALL机密码是
May I have your pager password?
林先生
Mr. Lin,
您没事吧
are you alright?
啊
What
我很好啊
I'm fine,
怎样
Why?
有没有留言啦
Any message?
今天下午3:05分
3:05 this afternoon, 045 said
045留言请您4点前到撞球间
Be at the Billiards House before 4.
一定要准时
You must be on time.
因为他们要埋伏
'Cause they plan an ambush.
嗯
Hum.
还有什么需要为您
Anything else I can do for you
感谢您的来电
Thank you for calling.
你知不知道菜脯
Do you know
喜欢什么样类型的女生啊
What kind of girl does Pickle like?
我啦
Me.
啊
What?
我啦
I said me.
啊不然菜脯喜欢吃什么
Well, what does Pickle like to eat?
面筋啦
Cheese.
对喔
Right!
“面筋”，“菜脯”
鈥淐heese鈥?and 鈥淧ickle
夹起来刚刚好
Perfect match.
来了来了
Here they come.
躲起来
Let's hide.
面筋
Cheese,
演像一点啦
play your role.
我知道啦
I know.
听说眷村仔在水闸门被人家打挂
I heard the Mainlanders were battered.
干！一定是阿信他们
It must be Ashin and his gang.
有够嚣张
They are everywhere.
我看这样啦
Well, how about this:
晚上来去找眷村仔乔这件事
We go to the Mainlanders tonight,
改天给他们好看
Together, we will teach Ashin's some lessons.
水啦
Good.
小姐，不好意思
Miss, Excuse me.
二号桌
Table 2.
新来的喔
You're new here?
水喔
Nice.
把马子喔
You're after this chick?
走啦
Let's go.
借我一下借我试一下
Excuse me.
没进去
Missed.
给你死
Kill them.
来啊～
Cheese,
面筋
are you alright?
你有没有怎样
Pickle,
菜脯，人家好害怕喔
I'm so scared.
喔！你也会怕喔
Oh, you are so scared.
你给我秀秀
I need some consolation.
真正有影
What the hell.
菜脯
Pickle, hurry up.
好，我给你秀秀
I give you my consolation.
菜脯，快一点
Pickle, come on!
来了啦
Coming.
不行
You can't do that!
啥款
How's that?
林先生您好
Hi, Mr. Lin.
937留言请您尽快赶到码头
937 said: be at the pier as soon as possible.
好累
Fuck, So tired.
啊～
What?
喔！抱歉啦
Sorry,
我不是在跟你讲啦
I wasn't talking to you.
拜拜
Bye.
菜脯
Pickle,
叫妈妈啦
Time to call momma.
（撞球场，胜二）
(Billiards House. Win: 2 times)
诶他是怎样
What's wrong with him?
不是你们体操队的
He was your teammate, right?
怎么每天都这张臭脸
How come he has this long face everyday?
诶这个圆的啤酒瓶仔
The round beer bottle
跟这四角的绍兴酒瓶
and the square ShaoShing bottle
哪一个打架起来比较好用
which one is better for fighting?
不知道
Don't know.
你不会试试看喔
Why don't you try la.
拿这个
Take this one.
抱歉喔
Excuse me.
阿娘喂
Shit.
妈咧
Holy shit.
这不是开玩笑的
This isn't funny.
叫阿嬷都会
Whoever get hit by this will call grandma
真正有影！
What the hell.
给它拜一下
Pray to la.
请它抽烟啦
Give ita cigarette.
有一块吗
Do you have a dollar?
这有
Here.
林先生您好
Hi, Mr. Lin.
嗯
Yes?
742留言
742 said:
请您半个小时后去钓虾场帮忙
He needs help at the shrimp pool 30 minutes later.
嗯
Okay.
诶，林先生
Mr. Lin
啊
What?
你之前去钓虾场三次都打输了
You have lost 3 fights at the shrimp pool
你这次要小心喔
So, be careful this time.
你怎么知道啊
How do you know?
呃
Well
因为我有帮你作纪录啊
'cause I'm keeping records for you.
啊
What?
没有啦
You know
因为你跟你朋友留言都很
The messages between you and your friends
特别
are very special.
而且我们公司电脑都有纪录啊
They're all in the company computer.
喔！这样哦
I see.
诶你有没有想过
Has itever occurred to you that
不要再过这种打打杀杀的生活啊
you should stop this kind of life?
没有耶
Nope.
诶你问这么多干嘛
Why are you asking?
没有啦
Nothing.
我只是想说
It seems to me, though,
你这样每天不是都过的很紧张吗
you life is very tense.
紧张什么
What is there to be tense for?
诶，我很好奇勒
Hey, I'm curious
你这边是电话秘书
You work for a pager service
还是那个什么张老师啊
or a counseling center?
啊
Well
还有啊
One more thing:
以后不要叫我林先生啦
Don't call me 鈥淢r. Lin" anymore.
叫我阿信
Call me Ashin.
阿信
Ashin.
拜拜
Bye.
小树
Shu
那两碗面端去给那桌的客人
These two bowls of noodle are for the quest over there
诶，吃快一点啦
Hey, eat faster.
看啥小
What are you looking at?
抱歉喔
Sorry.
老板，抱歉喔
Sorry, boss.
马上就好
Please wait a second.
小树
Shu,
那桌客人快要吃完了
That table is finishing soon.
赶快去收一收
Go clean the table.
快点
Hurry up.
赶快去收一收
Clean the table.
老板啊
Hey man,
哪有人这样做生意的
this is not how you do business.
位置这么少，客人要坐哪里
With so few seats, where shall we be seated?
面摊可以关一关了啦
Maybe you should shut the stall down.
赶快吃啦
Eat faster.
怎样啊，不爽喔
What? Any problem?
现在是怎样
You got something to say!
喔！抱歉啦
Oh, sorry!
不小心的啦
I didn't mean la.
找死喔
Are you looking for trouble?
你们如果那么饿
If you are that hungry
不然我“下面”给你们吃啦
how about I let you swallow my dick?
你皮在痒了
You asked for this.
也许这次就不是不小心的啰
Maybe I mean itthis time.
怎样
So?
免紧张啦
Take iteasy.
老大，抽烟啦
Boss. Have a cigarette.
你们两个胆识不错
You two really have balls.
以后就跟我
Come join my gang.
啥小
What the Fuck.
你爸我叫木瓜啦
I am Papaya.
我爸是黑松
My dad is Pine,
你是啥小
and who the hell you are?
黑松老大
His dad is Pine, the gang boss.
对
Yeah,
就是他
that's him.
跟我们比在这边卖水果有前途
Follow us get you farther than selling fruits.
有没有要买
Do you want to buy any fruit?
不然我要收摊了
We're closing.
好啊
Fine,
等你们收完摊
we can solve this
一起出来玩啊
after you close the shop.
甜的勒
These are sweet.
送给你们吃啦
You can have them for free.
甜的喔
Sweet papaya.
没关系
Don't worry.
你们忙
You guys are busy.
总会遇到的
We'll definitely be seeing each other again.
好吃耶
These are good.
你来干嘛
What do you want?
好啦，有麻烦可以来找我啦
I see, You can come to me for your trouble.
那找你回去
I come here to ask you back.
怎么样
What do you say?
回去
Going back?
练体操喔
To the gymnastics team?
跟你一样
And, be like you,
每天躲在体操馆
staying in the gym everyday,
过年只休两天
With only two days oh' during the Chinese New Year?
算了吧
Forget la.
太无聊了啦
It's too boring.
我现在才知道外面有多好玩
Now I know there is so much fun out here.
我以前怎么那么乖啊
How silly I was back then?
被体操绑得死死的
Tied myself to gymnastics.
哪像现在
See how free I am now?
我爱干什么就干什么
I can do whatever I want.
多爽啊
It is great!
是吗
IS la?
体操选手一辈子只有一次巅峰期
A gymnast has only one peak period in his life,
你再不回来，就来不及了
it'll be too late if you don't come back now.
真的假的啊
What are you talking about?
你以前不是最看不起我
You used to look down on me.
现在叫我回去
But now you're asking me back.
真正有影
(What me hell)
我告诉你
Listen,
如果我是练体操的料
if I am really good at gymnastics,
一年前教练就会把我留下来了
the coach wouldn't let me go a year ago.
不要怪别人
Stop blaming others.
你自己选的
This is your choice.
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请问您的CALL机密码是
May I have your pager password?
我是阿信啦
This is Ashin.
阿信
Ashin?
今天没有你的留言
There's no message for you today.
我知道啊
I know.
我打来
I called
是想跟你聊天啦
to talk to you.
很抱歉我们公司有规定
Sorry, but we're not allowed
不能跟客户聊天
to chat with clients.
我又不是你客户
I'm not your client,
我是你朋友勒
I'm a friend.
诶我在上班勒
I'm at work,
你不要闹啦
stop bugging me.
我哪有在闹啊
I am serious.
等你下班啦
Let's meet after you are off the clock
怎么样
How does that sound?
不行啦
No way.
为什么不行
Why not?
林先生，您不要这样
Mr. Lin, please do not act like this.
我在上班
I'm at work.
林先生喔
Mr. Lin
好啊
Fine.
那我留言可以吧
I want to leave a message, may I?
好的，请说
Yes, Go ahead.
今天晚上九点
9 o'clock tonight
电影院
at the movie theater.
不见不散
Be there or be square.
您的留言代号是
To whom you leave this message?
Y-O-U
Y, O, U.
YOU啦
YOU.
你除了玩跟打架
Is there anything meaningful to you
没有更有意义的事情可以做吗
other than fooling around and fight?
喂
Hello?
那你每天在这里接电话
So your life is more meaningful
就比我有意义啦
answering phone calls every day?
感谢您的来电
Thank you for calling.
诶，你们第一次来喔
Is this your first time here?
我也第一次来勒
It is mine.
嗨～
Hi.
坐啦
Have a sit.
免紧张啊
Take iteasy.
我就跟你说宜兰没多大
Told you Yilan is a small place,
我们总会遇到的啦
and we'll meet again on way or the other.
抽烟啦
Have a cigarette.
现在流行抽这个啦
This is what's popular now.
怎样
What?
你怕喔
You're scared?
诶
Hey.
阿信啊，你怎么那么晚才来
Ashin, you're so late.
人家都休息了啊
Everyone had left.
不好意思啦
I'm sorry.
来
Come on.
赶快搬一搬啦
Get the cartons and move fast,
我要回去睡我的美容觉
I'll go back for my beauty sleep.
赶快搬啦
Hurry up.
诶等一下啦
Wait a second.
等一下啦
Wait up
菜脯
Pickle!
等一下
Wait for me.
菜脯
Pickle!
Pickle,
菜脯，有没有怎样
Pickle, are you okay?
爽啦
Fucking awesome.
真的假的啊
Are you serious?
嗯
Yap
诶，你最近怪怪的
You've been acting weird recently.
一个礼拜没睡觉喔
I haven't slept for a week.
啥
What?
诶晚上陪我去把马子
Lets go get some actions tonight.
顺便教我那个
And you can teach me
“大车轮”
the 鈥渂ig wheel
嘿！菜脯
Hey, Pickle.
嘿！
Hey.
你也来跳舞喔
You come here to dance, too?
打架厉害
You may know how to fight,
跳舞不一定厉害喔
but not necessarily know how to dance.
去啦，输人不输阵
It's your turn.
妈勒，我又不会跳舞
I don't know how.
你就跟体操一样翻来翻去
Just as you do gymnastics.
去啦
Go.
他是我兄弟啊
He's my buddy.
阿信
Ashin.
这我兄弟啦
This is my buddy.
怎样
So?
不要吵
Quiet.
老大，让他难看
Boss, show him what you got.
老大，跟他拼了
Boss, beat him.
来啊
Come on.
诶小心喔
Watch out.
拜拜
Bye.
阿信我一定要让他死
I will definitely kill Ashin.
老大
Boss,
其实你跳的不错啊
you weren't so bad, actually.
只是那个后空翻
You just need to
还要再练一下
work on that somersault.
喝酒啦
Shut up and drink.
跳到肚子饿啰
Got hungry after dancing?
来吃面喔
You're here for noodles?
坐啊
Have a seat.
没有啦
Well
你那边还有吗
Do you have more?
有啊
Of course.
叫多少都算我的
Order all you want and it's my treat.
不要这样啦
Come on.
不然～
How about
我跟你买
I buy from you?
你要买喔
You want to buy from me?
你不是很厉害
I thought you know your ways around.
你爸我不爽卖
I don't want to sell itto you.
怎样
What?
你不爽喔
Are you angry?
不然你去找你朋友阿信啊
Why not ask Ashin for help?
木瓜老大
Mr. Papaya,
对不起啦
Sorry
阿信他不是故意的
Ashin didn't mean to embarrass you.
你不要跟他计较啦
Please don't be angry with him.
对不起
Sorry.
叫他来
Get him here.
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请问您的CALL机密码是
May I have your pager password?
林先生您好
Hi, Mr. Lin.
您有一则新留言
You have one new message.
菜脯约您一起吃宵夜
From Pickle: night snack together.
嗯
Okay.
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请问您的CALL机密码是
May I have your pager password?
我啦
It's me,
阿信啦
Ashin.
还在生气喔
Are you still mad at me?
气那么久喔
It's been a while
不要气了啦
Don't be mad.
我没有啊
I am not.
没有
No?
真的没有
Are you sure?
今天很难得嘛
It's kind of rare that
不是去打架是去吃宵夜啊
You're going for snack instead a fight tonight.
对啊
Yeah.
你几点下班
When you are off duty?
我来接你
I'll pick you up and
一起吃宵夜啊
we can have snack together.
很抱歉
Sorry,
我们公司有规定
We are not allowed
喔～
Come on.
你很难约耶
You're hard to get.
真正有影
What the hell
诶，看一下窗外
Look out from your window.
看一下看一下
Take a look.
我在你公司楼下
I'm downstairs by your office.
诶那是谁啊
Who is that?
我是阿信～
I am Ashin.
跟我约会吧
Let's go out together.
他是来找谁的啊
Who is he looking for?
都收摊了
Snack my ass,
还叫我来吃面
the noodle stall is closed?
真正有影
What the hell.
菜脯～
Pickle?
菜脯？
在这边啦
Here.
连你也肚子饿了喔
So you are hungry, too? Huh?
我跟你说过嘛
I told you, right?
交朋友不是比较好
Isn't it better if we are friends?
老大
Boss.
老大～
怎么会这样
How could this happen?
老大
Boss.
你有没有怎么样
Are you alright?
老大，怎么办
Boss.
走
Go!
该怎么办
Do something
惨了
Damn
走
Go!
快走
Hurry up!
开门
Open the door.
急救箱
First aid kit!
哥，你怎么啦
Brother, what's wrong?
急救箱啊
First aid kit!
快一点
Hurry up!
碘酒
Iodine.
绷带
Bandage.
啊是怎么了
What's going on?
你怎么全身都是血
Why are you covered in blood?
是发生什么事情你说啊
What happened?
到底怎样，你快说啊
Tell me! Tell me what happened!
要说什么
Tell you what?
人都死了
Someone died!
是要说什么
What can I say?
哥
Brother,
你到底怎么了
what happened to you?
跑路
I have to run away.
为什么
Why?
有时候你不找麻烦
Sometimes trouble finds you
麻烦也会找上你
even when you're not looking for it.
阿信
Ashin.
这个带着
Take this with you.
没钱是要怎么跑路
You can't run away without money.
等一下
Wait.
来不及了
We don't have time.
等一下啦
Wait a second.
这个玉镯你也带着
Take this jade bracelet, too.
快走快走
Go! Hurry!
快走
Hurry up!
走远一点
Go as far as you can.
快走远一点
Just go.
菜脯
Pickle,
对不起
I am sorry.
阿信
Ashin,
对不起
I am sorry.
你哥呢
Where's your brother?
不知道啦
I don't know.
再问你一次
Let me ask you again,
你哥咧
where's your brother?
就不知道嘛
I said I don't know.
有种喔
You think you have guts.
给我打
Beat him.
再嚣张嘛
How about now?
再嚣张啊
And now?
这是什么
What's this?
巧克力喔
Chocolate?
还我啦
Give it back to me.
不还你啦！怎样
Hell, no!
来拿啊
Come get it.
还我
Give it back to me.
怎样，不还啦！怎样
What? What are you gonna do?
老大，你有没有怎样
Boss, are you okay?
鼻子流血了啦
My nose is bleeding.
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请问您的CALL机密码是
May I have your pager password?
阿信
Ashin,
你你还好吗
are you okay?
给我的留言应该都很吓人吧
My messages are frightening, right?
快
Yes.
我只有投一块钱
Hurry up, I only put in a dollar.
好
Okay.
610说他们老大黑松已经对你
610 said the big boss Pine ordered
下了追杀令
to kill you.
你逃不掉的
You cannot escape.
下一个
Next.
742留言说他有请他大哥帮你乔
742 said his boss tried to put in good words for you,
但是他大哥也被打了
but his boss was also thrashed.
现在其他人都不敢帮你乔
No one dares to say anything anymore.
还有呢
What else?
你弟弟小贤留言
Your little Brother Xian said
说他不怕麻烦了
he is not afraid of trouble now.
要你好好照顾自己
And you take care of yourself.
还有其他留言吗
Anything else?
阿信
Ashin
599留言
A message from 599,
要你有耐心
you have to be patient.
一定会有出路的
There'll be a way out.
599?
谁啊
Who is it?
喂～
Hello?
菜脯
Pickle,
Pickle.
起来啦
Time to get up.
不要吵
Leave me alone.
你不是三天不睡
You either stay up for three days
就是一次睡三天
or you sleep for three days.
你是猪喔
Are you a pig?
吃饭了啦
It's time to eat.
你去哪里
Where did you go?
找工作啊
Looking for a job.
不然吃什么
Or how do we feed ourselves?
你那边有没有钱
Do you have more money?
先借我一点啦
Lend me some.
没有啦
I have nothing.
哪来的钱
Where do I come up with any money?
你买便当还有剩吗
Anything left after you bought the lunchbox?
先借我一点啦
Lend me some.
没有啦
I said no.
给你去买安喔
So you can buy amphetamine?
我们不是兄弟吗
I thought we're buddies.
我们是兄弟勒
We're buddies!
你看我这么难过
You enjoy seeing me
你会爽喔
as painful as this?
先借我一点啦
Just lend me some money.
吃不吃啦
You want this or not?
好
Fine.
你不吃是不是
You don't want to eat?
以后什么都不要吃啦
Don't you eat a damn thing then.
你生气了喔
Are you angry?
阿信
Ashin.
你不要生气啦
Don't be angry.
不要生气啦
我吃啦
I'll eat.
你不要生气啦
Don't be angry.
我们会这样
We are here like this
还不都是为了你
all because of you.
我们是兄弟勒
We're buddies.
都不要让我买到
Better not let me buy the drug ever.
林家祖先
The ancestors of the Lin family,
你要保佑阿信
please bless Ashin.
在外面要会想
Let him know what is right
要自己照顾自己
and be able to take care of himself.
你要保佑他平安啊
Please bless him to be safe.
老大
Boss,
坤大说
Master Kun said,
这次不管喝多少都算他的
whatever we drink today,
今天他特别招待我们
it's on him.
招待
It's a special offer.
招待个屁啊
Special offer my ass.
招待
I don't care.
这间店迟早我会把它收起来
I'll take over this place sooner or later.
是不会叫老板喔
Don't you know how to greet us?
新来的
You're new to here?
嗯
Hum.
谢谢
Thank you.
妈咧
Shit.
认真一点啦
Be serious.
啥小啦
What the fuck.
少爷
Waiter.
桌面是不会整理一下喔
Come clean the fucking table.
你耳聋啰
Are you deaf?
你是想怎样
What the fuck?
抱歉，抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
怎样
What?
大哥，抱歉
Sorry, boss.
你别跟他计较
Please forgive him.
你要挺他吗
You want to stand up for him?
Do you want to stand up for him?
找死喔
Damn! You're dead.
老大
Boss,
抱歉啦
I'm sorry.
菜脯
Pickle.
这样可以吗
Is this okay?
你头壳坏了
You're god damn nuts.
不行喔
Not enough?
这样应该可以了吧
How about this?
菜脯
Pickle.
现在是吵够了没
Enough!
菜脯
Pickle,
你干什么啦
what are you doing?
疯牛
Mad Ox.
你还真爱到处乱玩喔
You do like to jab around.
玩到我店里来了
Now you're having fun in my place.
坤大
Master Kun,
你店里什么时候玩这么刺激
I don't know when your joint
我怎么不知道
has become such an exciting place.
有饭大家吃啦
There are enough for everyone.
你都不怕吃太快
But, if you want to grab them all,
把碗都给砸了
you might break the bowl.
大家都没饭吃喔
Nothing will be left in the end.
我们年轻人就是要吃你
We are young and we want to grab.
不然你想怎样
Any problem?
那现在都见血了
Now someone has bled.
你还想怎样
What else do you want?
坤哥都这样说了
Well, since Master Kun said so
带他去看医生
Take him to the doctor.
坤大，谢谢
Master Kun, thank you.
给你死
You're dead.
你还跑
Now you're running
还跑
Still running
好啊
Great
你还跑
Still running
跑快一点啊
It that your best
你要去哪里啊
Where're you going?
你爸送你去啦
I'll take you son of bitch there.
把疯牛处理掉
If you can get rid of Mad Ox,
这一百万就你们的
this one million dollars will be yours.
谢谢坤大
Thank you, Master Kun.
没有啦
Well,
坤大
Master Kun,
我们
We
没关系
it's okay.
这件事就当我没提过
Let's forget about this.
来
Cheers.
菜脯
Pickle,
台北我住不惯
Taipei is not for me.
不会啊
I feel different.
我感觉很好啊
I am very contented here.
好在哪里
Contented?
我们来台北是为了什么
Why did we come to Taipei?
不是为了来作别人小弟
We didn't come here to be someones thugs.
拜托勒
Come on,
怎么会
what gave you that thought?
我们是什么
What are we?
绍兴酒瓶勒
We're ShaoShing bottles.
有多强啦
You think it's strong?
还不是一样会破
It can still be shattered.
菜脯
Pickle.
跟我回宜兰
Let's go back to Yilan.
怎么回去
How?
你以为我没有想过喔
You think I never thought about it?
我们现在回去
If we go back now,
不是被抓去关
we'll either end up in prison
就是被人打死在路边
or be beaten to death.
那又怎样
So?
有问题我们可以一起解决啊
We can solve problems together.
就像以前一样
Just as the old days.
但人是我杀的
It 's me who killed him.
以前是我不够强
I was not strong enough
所以才会变成这样
so we end up like this.
我要留在台北
I'm staying in Taipei.
你看
You'll see,
我告诉你
I'm telling you
我马上就会做老大了
I'll become a gangster head soon.
以后发生什么事情
If anything happens in the future,
换我罩你
it'll be my turn to cover you.
你罩我
You cover me?
你怎么罩我
How can you cover me?
你干嘛这样看我啦
Why are you looking at me like this?
你想要啦我喔
Do you want to kiss me?
喝啦
Just drink some more.
菜脯？菜脯？
Pickle? Pickle?
阿信诶
Ashin,
我跟你说
you see, that night
那天晚上为了安非他命
I wanted the amphetamine so much,
骗你出来吃面
that I lied to get you out
害到你被人家打
and you were beaten so badly.
我真的很没用
I'm such a loser.
对不起
I am sorry.
我不配当你的兄弟
I don't deserve to be your buddy.
你就回去宜兰好好练体操啦
You shall go back to Yilan and do your gymnastics.
这钱跟玉佩
The money and the jade pendants
拿给我爸爸
are for my dad.
说以后他再也打不到我了
Tell him he can't beat me anymore.
要好好照顾自己
Ask him to take care of himself.
要他记得
Tell him to remember that
他曾经有个老婆和一个儿子
he had a wife and a son.
P.S.
面筋如果问起我
If Cheese asked about me,
你就跟她说
tell her, just as the song says:
“忘了你，忘了我”
鈥淔orget you, forget me."
菜脯
Pickle,
再嚣张啊
Let's play tougher
起来啊
Get up!
快爬起来啊
Get up, you punk.
走
Let's go.
这样我就可以回宜兰了
Now, I can go back to Yilan.
阿信～
Ashin.
菜脯！
Pickle!
菜脯～
你为什么就是不听我的
Why didn't you listen to me?
你不是说你要当老大吗
You said you'll become the head.
你要罩我的吗
You said you'll cover me.
菜脯～
Pickle
有留言吗
Any message?
很多通留言
A lot.
是不是都在干礁我
All nasty ones?
嗯
Right.
不听了
Forget it.
你觉得
Do you think
我应该回去吗
I should go back?
你怎么那么喜欢待在这里啊
Why do you like it here so much?
阿信
Ashin,
你要不要干脆回来练体操啊
Why don't you just come back to the gymnastic team?
我看你每次打架
You fight
都像成龙一样翻来翻去
as good as Jackie Chan.
很厉害勒
That is amazing.
你没看到我的棋在这里
You didn't see my defense
照吃啦
I'll take you after all
笨象，你这只笨象
Dumb Knight, I'm taking you down
快点，换你了
Come on, your turn
老大
Boss.
人来了
Here he is.
你还敢来
How dare you to come here?
我来
I'm here,
我来是想解决问题
because I want to solve the problem.
过来
Come here.
再过来一点
Come closer.
你真的不怕死
You're not afraid of death?
老大
Boss,
这小子如果这么有种
if he is really not afraid of death,
干脆就完成他的愿望啦
we can make his dream come true.
那不然剁他的脚啦
We can cut oh' his legs.
剁手啦
Or the hands.
剁脚剁手
Cut off his legs, hands
连他那个也剁掉拿去喂鳄鱼啦
and his dick to feed the crocodile.
你们两个是那边爽什么
You guys are really enjoying this, huh?
阿信
Ashin!
你还敢来
How dare you to come here!
爸～给他死啦
Dad, let's take him out.
少爷
Master.
好了啦
Shut up.
我知道这个死孩子
I know this asshole dealt drugs
偷偷在我背后卖安非他命
behind my back.
我也知道
I also know that
我也知道是他先带人打你
the whole mess was
才会发生这一堆有的没的事
because he beat you in first place.
但是不管怎么说
Even so, it's the son of mine
今天是我黑松的儿子被打
that was beaten.
这要是传出去能听吗
I can not bear to lose the face.
我问你
Let me ask you,
你明知道我不会放过你
why did you come back
你怎么还敢回来啊
when you knew I won't be easy on you?
因为我要翻身
'Cause I want a new start.
我要重新练体操
I want to go back to gymnastics.
体操
Gymnastics?
你是说那种翻来翻去的体操吗
That jumping and rolling thing?
等一下就没手没脚了
You'll lose your hands and legs soon,
我看你要怎么翻
I would love to see you roll
闭嘴啦
Shut up.
好
Nice,
练体操
gymnastics.
我给你一年的时间
I will give you a year.
一年内
You have to win a gold medal
你一定要给我拿到金牌
within one year.
要不然就不是在这池
If not, you won't be bathing in this one
而是在隔壁那池
but that one.
来
Hey,
集合
assemble here.
你们是从小
You're hand-picked gymnasts
就挑选出来的选手
since you were kids.
在这个中间
Over times,
也有很多人选择离开
many chose to leave.
既然你们选择留下
For those who chose to stay,
就请你们尊重你们自己的选择
please respect your own choice,
也尊重这项运动
and respect this sport.
阿信
Ashin.
一二
One, two.
高一点喔
Higher.
一
One.
顶住
Hold it.
二
Two.
阿伯
Old man,
还可以吧
are you okay?
别吵
Shut up!
一二三四五六七八九十
1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10.
快
Go, sprint!
冲刺冲刺喔
I said sprint!
该戒烟了吧
Time to quit smoking.
我看你这个体能啊
You're not capable of
你还不能练单项
practicing individual event yet.
来来来，起来起来起来
Get up from there.
先去给我跑操场
Go to run on the field first.
老大
Boss,
我看他差不多了
He looks exhausted.
来～来～
Let' go.
阿信
Ashin,
你爸我这次一定要给你死啊
I'll kill you this time.
有胆别跑啊
Don't go! Go to hell!
你不是很带种
Where did you put your balls?
有胆别跑啊
Why don't you stop and fight?
谢谢你愿意原谅阿信
Thank you for giving Ashin a chance.
你不要跑那么快啦
Don't run so fast.
有一半理由是因为你
Half the reason is of you,
另一半是因为他自己
the other half is of he himself.
这小子个性有够强
He is a really stubborn young man.
他的个性跟你年轻的时候很像勒
He's quite like the younger you.
像我
Me?
你也看一下
Come on.
我的体能比他好太多了吧
I'm much stronger than he is.
对啦
Yeah.
那个时候你是队上最强的
You were the best among the team.
唉～
Alas.
强有什么用
Strong? So what?
还不是要吃饭拉屎
You still need to eat and shit.
这小子有心想要练
He does want to do gymnastics.
你觉得他有希望吗
Do you think he has prospects?
年底有个国际体操邀请赛
There is an international game at the end of the year.
我也没把握他能不能上场比赛
I am not sure if he can make it.
你是教练勒
You're the coach!
这种话你也说的出来
You shouldn't say this.
好好给我操一下
Train him seriously.
不要给我漏气喔
Don't you lose my face.
你是流氓勒
Come on, you're a gang master.
我哪敢给你漏气喔
How would I dare to lose your face?
好啦好啦
Fine.
不要说这个啦
Quit it.
诶你看
Look
从现在我不会再逃避
I will not run away anymore
重新的唤起
Face the calling
埋藏在我心底的血液
the blood running deep within my heart.
沉住气
Stay focused.
我的，心不再移
I will not be astray again.
屏息不放弃
Hold my breath, never give up.
慢慢的
Slowly,
朝着我的梦前进
I walk toward my dream.
忘了吧
Forget it.
混乱的事不再提
Don't mention the mess.
放了吧
Let it go.
把心思变唯一
Focus on one thing only.
我会用尽所有力
I'll do my best.
奋力的跃起在天际
Leap as high as the sky.
迎着光明
Toward the brightest.
我会更用力呼吸
I'll breath harder.
飞到另一个灿烂天空
Fly into another brilliant sky.
完美
Perfect.
落地
Landing.
阿信
Ashin
Ashin.
你过来一下
Come here.
教练
Coach.
把手放上来
Put your hand here.
抚摸它
Touch it.
把它想像成是一匹真的马
Think of it as a real horse.
抚摸它的毛
Stroke its hair.
跟它说话
Talk to it:
感谢你
Thank you.
因为有你
We can do this sport
我们才能从事这项运动
only because of you.
教练
Coach,
你在干嘛
what are you doing?
跟它说话啊
Talking to it.
男子体操啊
Man gymnastics events are:
地板、鞍马、吊环
Floor Exercise, Pommel Horse, Still Rings
跳马、双杠、单杠
Vault, Parallel Bars, Horizontal bar
这六个项目
Six in total.
全都是冰冷的器材
They are all performed on cold facilities.
如果你没有热情
If you don't learn to feel them,
如果你不跟它建立关系
don't build relationships with them,
你就永远无法控制你的恐惧
you can never overcome your fears to them.
运用你的想像力
So, use your imagination.
跟它说话
Talk to it.
懂了吗
Get it?
所以你跟教练两个人
So you and the coach have stroked
就站在那里摸跳马摸十分钟喔
the vault for an entire 10 minutes?
对啊
Yeah.
很好笑喔
It is funny, isn't it?
不会呀
No.
把跳马当成活的
Does it make you feel better
有让你感觉比较好吗
when thinking it as something alive?
好像是有点用啦
Kind of.
但我觉得最大的问题
But my biggest problem
还是在我自己身上
comes from myself.
如果没办法克服我的左腿
If I don't overcome my left leg,
很难会有好成绩
I can never get a good result.
阿信
Ashin.
嗯
What?
其实我很羡慕你是个体操选手
Actually, I envy you because you're a gymnast.
是喔
Oh yeah?
嗯
Yes.
我曾经是个游泳选手
I was a swimmer.
妈勒
Holy crap!
真的假的
Really?
那你穿泳衣一定很好看哦
You must look great in swimming suit.
喂
Hey,
人家很认真耶
I'm serious.
好啦好啦
Fine.
那你还有在游吗
Do you still swim?
不游了
Not anymore.
为什么
Why?
阿信
Ashin.
你要坚持下去
You must hang on.
你不光是为了自己奋斗
You fight not only for yourself
也是替那些曾经有梦想的人奋斗
but for those who had dreams.
喔～对了
One more thing.
有一通599的留言
You have a message from 599.
她说
She said:
加油
Go for it!
我知道了
I got it.
哥
Brother,
爸快要死了
dad is dying.
妈叫我们回去帮他换衣服
Mom wants us to go home and change dad's clothes.
爸
Dad?
哥，你在干嘛
Brother, what are you doing?
阿爸有说过
Dad said, if you feel like crying
想哭的时候就倒立
you can do handstand.
这样眼泪就不会流下来了
So the tears won't fall down.
对啊
This is it!
把不够的补满
Add to what is needed.
把不足的长度补齐
Fill the short one to the right length.
很感谢你
Thank you for taking care of Ashin
阿信住这边都托你照顾
while he's staying here.
不要这样说
Never mind.
事情有解决就好
As long as the problems are solved.
阿信喔
Ashin
你来干嘛
What are you doing here?
为什么你就是不让我练体操啊
Why cant you just let me do gymnastics?
你把我害的还不够惨吗
You want to see me live in hell again?
阿信
Ashin
为什么你连让我重新作人的机会
Why do you want to deprive me
都不给我
of the chance to have a new life?
我就一定得回去卖水果
You want me to sell fruit again?
我的人生是我在过的
This is my life,
不是你
not yours.
林太太
Mrs. Lin Mrs. Lin
教练
Coach,
不管我妈怎么说
no matter what my mom said,
我这次绝对不会退出体操队
I will not leave the team this time.
这双鞋你先拿着
Hold the shoes first.
这双鞋的左脚
The left one has special pad and sole
有特制加厚的鞋垫与鞋底
with just the right thickness.
长度刚好可以让你的两条腿
So the lengths of your legs
变得一样长
can become even.
我想了很久了
I thought about this for a long time.
这是唯一可以解决你长短腿的办法
It's the only solution to your legs.
谢谢教练
Thank you, coach.
你不用谢我
Not me,
要谢啊
If there's anyone to thank,
谢你妈
it's your mom.
你知道你小时候得过小儿麻痹吗
Do you know you had Polio?
你妈一直为这件事情很自责
She has been blaming herself for it.
她说是她没有把你照顾好
She said it's her fault that
所以才让你生病
led to your illness.
还好她从小
Thanks to her massaging your leg everyday
就每天帮你按摩你的脚
since you were a kid,
要不然你的左脚
or your left leg would wither
会萎缩的比现在更严重
even more seriously than it is now.
你懂了吗
Do you get it?
不要动啦
Don't move.
妈，为什么你要按哥哥的脚啊
Mom, why are you massaging Brother's leg?
就是这样经常按经常推
The constant massage
哥哥才会长大啊
can make your brother grow up.
好吃的来啰
Here comes the good one.
妈
Mom,
这是什么
what's this?
吃腿补腿啊
Eat legs for better legs.
你快要比赛了啊
Your game is coming.
吃这个田鸡腿比较会跳
Frog legs can help you jump higher.
妈
Mom
我不用比赛
I am not competing,
我不用吃
so I don't have to eat.
你小时候不是最会吵
You used to say that
吵着要长大
you want to be a grown-up.
就要吃这个才会长大
Eat this so you can be a grown-up.
知道吗
See?
我不要吃啦
I don't want to.
吃啦 赶快吃啦
Eat it.
不要弄你弟弟啦
Don't tease your younger brother.
妈
Mom
没办法啊
I can't help you
你哥哥都喜欢欺负你
Your older brother has been fond of teasing you
阿爸
Dad, please bless me
你要保佑我这个月考试一百分
to get A+ in my test this month,
然后妈妈身体健康
and mom to be healthy,
还有哥哥拿到跳马金牌
and brother to win the Vault Gold Medal.
不要一次跟你爸求那么多啦
Don't make so many wishes.
你要把他累死喔
Your dad will be exhausted.
这我来就好
I'll take care of them.
给他死啦
Kill them.
来～冲刺喔冲刺喔
Come on, sprint. Sprint!
冲刺喔
Sprint!
水啦
Nice!
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎莅临1994年国际体操邀请赛
Welcome to 1994 international invitation gymnastics competition.
让我们用最热烈的掌声欢迎
Let's give our warmest welcome
男子组跳马个人总决赛选手进场
to the finalists of Vault Event.
妈，这是你第一次来看哥哥比赛
Mom, it's your first time to see brother's game.
对啊
Yeah.
好多人啊
There're so many people.
你哥在哪
Where's your brother?
在那边，在那边
Over there.
阿爸
Dad,
阿信在那里
Ashin's there.
你把我挡住了
You're in my way.
我怎么看
I can't see.
在哪
Where is he?
第一位登场的选手是
Our first contestant is from
中华台北何正树
Chinese Taipei, Ho Zheng-Shu.
水啦
Nice!
水喔
9.5
You got 9.5.
现在恭喜还太早
It's too early to congratulate me.
你还没有跳
You haven鈥檛 jumped yet.
我又不一定赢得了你
I don't think I can get higher point than you.
我现在终于知道
I finally know that
要嬴别人很容易
it's easy to surpass others.
最难的是嬴自己
What's difficult is to top oneself.
站在选手立场
As a contestant,
我不希望你嬴
I don't want you to win.
但站在朋友立场
But as a friend, I hope
我希望你嬴
you have the best performance.
华生电信您好
This is Huasheng Telecom.
请问您的CALL机密码是
May I have your pager password?
你是
You're not
之前那位电话秘书咧
What happen to the previous girl?
您说599吗
You mean 599?
她离职啰
She has quit.
请问您是林先生吗
Are you Mr. Lin?
我是
Yes, I am.
599有留言给您
599 left you a message.
请问您要听吗
Do you want to hear it?
好
Yes.
阿信
Ashin,
很高兴认识你
it's nice to know you.
因为你
Because of you
我才下定决心辞职
I made up my mind to quit my job.
我对你有很深的期待
I have great expectation about you.
你不只是为了自己奋斗
You fight not only for yourself,
也是替那些曾经有梦想的人奋斗
but for those who once had dreams.
你还记不记得
Do you still remember
599曾经留言给你
that message from 599?
她说
She said:
如果你还有梦
If you still have a dream,
就该勇敢去追
then go for it bravely.
我记得
I remember.
嗯
Yes.
599也要勇敢去追梦了
599 is going after her dream now.
加油
Go for it.
接下来登场的是中华台北选手 林育信
The next contestant is from Chinese Taipei, Lin Yu-shin.
阿信
Ashin!
啥款
What's up?
1978 Ashin with his dad and younger brother.
1980 Ashin learnt gymnastic leg-lift.
1983 Ashin won the first Vault Gold Medal.
1987 Ashin became a gangster.
1994 Like a black horse, as soon as Ashin returned to gymnastic world,
he won the National Golden Medal in Vault and Floor Exercise.
啥款
How's that?
眼睛不用张那么大
Don't be so surprised.
千真万确
Don't doubt,
这个人就是我
that's me.
原来交朋友是这种感觉
So that's what friends are like.
诶那你球棒可以还我吗
Can I have my bat back?
诶你要不要跳啊
Are you going to jump or not?
站在那边站那么久
You've been standing there for so long.
你练那么久
You've practiced for so long.
还没准备好喔
Aren't you ready for this?
还没～
Not yet.
体操选手不是随时都要准备好吗
Gymnast should always be ready.
不管什么时候都可以上
You can do your moves at anytime.
你忘记了吗
Don't you remember?
冲过来
Come on.
加油
Go for this!
Go!
啊
Ah!
哥，快来救我啦
Brother, come to help me!
哥，快来啦
Brother, hurry up!
哥
Brother!